Guide to the J.L. Hargett Collection of Choctaw Nation Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Documents and Financial Papers, 1830-1908; Series II; 1.09; (2.5 boxes)
  - DOCUMENTS
    - Other Documents
      - Minutes of Oklahoma Congressional Committee Meeting held in Coalgate on December 14th 1907, 1908 Jan 21 (Box 3, Folder 107)
      - List of Choctaw orphan children in Moshulatubbee and Nettuckachee Districts (Box 3, Folder 108)
      - List of Choctaw names attending opening conference of [---?] (Box 3, Folder 109)
      - List of cattle that was given up to the government in 1833, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 110)
      - Statement concerning Choctaw Indians during the Civil War (Box 3, Folder 111)
      - Summary of birth certificate for Edmund M. McKinney (Box 3, Folder 112)
      - Summary of a title search, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - FINANCIAL PAPERS
    - Statements of account, 1833-70, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 114-115)
      Stored also in: Oversize, box 4, folder 144
    - Personal statements of debt, 1838-98 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Receipts, 1844-97, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Bills of sale, 1853-1904 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - LeFlore, Forbis. Memorandum book with accounts, receipts, prescriptions, and other notes, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Claim of money by Tandy Walker against Thomson McKenney, 1860-63 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Financial records of Choctaw Nation school districts 1868-1870, [1868-70] (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Financial records relating to the repair of Spencer Academy by Norris & Ervin, 1869 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Statement of money received from the U.S. Government from July 1870-June 1871
    - Chattel Mortgage: T. J. Philpin to J. H. Carson, 1898 Aug 3 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Expenses for a trip by unidentified people, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Statement of Funds turned over to Basil L. LeFlore Treasurer of the Choctaw Nation by Geo. T. Olmsted Capt. U.S.A. and U.S. Indian Agent
- Other Papers, 1870-1917; Series III; 0.21; (.5 boxes)
  Series III, Other Papers, is organized into three subseries: Writings, Printed Material and Miscellaneous Papers.
  - WRITINGS
    - Address to new Choctaw sabbath school. Manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Hatuk nanpisa Iholiso oke. Choctaw paper relating to a legislative council? Manuscript, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - History of rule of Col. Greenwood LeFlore and David Folsom in the Choctaw Nation. Incomplete manuscript (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - "Items for Forbis LeFlore's speech" [to Choctaw Council] Manuscript, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Lord's Prayer in Choctaw. Manuscript, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Memoir of Mr. Nathaniel Folsom as detailed by himself to Cyrus Byington, June, 1829. Manuscript, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Perry, A. E. Speech to Progressive Club Banquet, "Future Oklahoma from Non Partisan view." Manuscript, 1909 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Poem for Forbis and Phebe's wedding. Manuscript (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - PRINTED MATERIAL
    - Boonsboro Female Seminary Washington County, Arkansas. Advertisement, 1871 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Department of the Interior, Commission to the Five Civilized Tribes. Table of Classification and Appraisement of Lands in the Choctaw and Chickasaw Nations., 1902 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Catalogue of Cane Hill College, Cane Hill, Arkansas, for the Scholastic Year, 1870-71 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Notice and clipping relating to A. E. Perry, 1890, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Clippings: advertisements from Tishomingo City, Indian Territory, 1881, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Clippings related to Coalgate, Oklahoma, 1917, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS
    - List of David Folsom's accomplishments. Holograph, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Miscellaneous notes and scraps possibly relating to A. E. Perry (Box 3, Folder 140)
      Found with A. E. Perry letters
    - Recipe for milk paint, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - List of livestock, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 142)
- Oversize, 1.2; (1 box)
  Oversize contains oversize material from series II, and is listed in box order.
  - Lists of Choctaw names and signatures (in Series II) (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 143)
  - Statements of account (in Series II), 1833-70, n.d. (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 144)
  - Statement of money received from the U.S. Government from July 1870-June 1871 (in Series II) (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 145)
  - Statement of Funds turned over to Basil L. LeFlore Treasurer of the Choctaw Nation by Geo. T. Olmsted Capt. U.S.A. and U.S. Indian Agent (in Series II) (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 146)
  - List of land scrip "cases all just in" (incomplete) (in Series II) (Box bsd, folder 147)
  - Petition to the Chiefs of the General Council of the Choctaw Nation that the Choctaw Nation ask the United States Government to honor the treaty of Dancing Rabbit Creek (in Series II), 1849 (Box port, folder 148)
  - Petition to General Council to appoint Thomson McKenney as Choctaw delegate. Signed by a long list of Choctaw Indians (in Series II), [ca. 1850] (Box port, folder 149)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.21; (1 box)
  Restricted Fragile Papers contains fragile originals. The material is arranged in folder order and may only be seen with the permission of the appropriate curator.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, folder 14 (Box 5, Folder 150)
  - Box 1, folder 48 (Box 5, Folder 151)
  - Box 3, folder 138 (Box bsd, folder 152)